jaycar.com.au 2018-05-04

# Privacy Policy | Jaycar Electronics

## **Privacy Policy**

Jaycar Pty Ltd (Jaycar) is committed to protecting the privacy of all individuals. To deliver our commitment to privacy, we will comply with the legislation and regulations of the countries in which we operate. This statement provides a succinct overview of how we handle personal information. This Privacy Policy was updated March 2014. As an Australian registered company, Jaycar is bound by the current Privacy Act, any amendments and the Australian Privacy Principles (APPs) contained within that Act. All employees and officers of Jaycar are required to comply with the Act and this Privacy Statement. Jaycar has a Privacy Act Procedure which can be obtained by emailing privacyofficer@jaycar.com.au. Information or opinions which are collected, held, used or disclosed by Jaycar about an individual whose identity is apparent, or can reasonably be ascertained, will be protected by the standards outlined in this Statement. To deliver our commitment to privacy, we will:

• Be bound by, and comply with, the APPs under the Act in relation to personal information  
• Communicate this Privacy Statement to all employees and stakeholders to ensure awareness of their requirement to comply with our privacy standards and to anyone else who asks for it  
• Ensure lawful, fair and unobtrusive means are used to collect personal information that is necessary for our business purposes  
• Collect sensitive information only with the individual’s consent and not disclose any personal information to an unrelated third party, except with the individual’s consent or where we are required to do so by law  
• Take reasonable steps to destroy or de-identify personal information in a secure manner when we have no further need for it or are required to do so by law   
• Ensure only authorised personnel who have agreed to keep personal information confidential have access to the information   
• Take reasonable steps to keep personal information up to date, accurate and complete  
• Provide individuals access to their personal information on request  
• Periodically review and revise this Privacy Statement and related procedures to maintain relevance.

Jaycar recognises and respects the importance of each individual’s privacy. This Statement and related procedures ensure all personal information held by Jaycar is handled appropriately and kept confidential.

What do we use personal information for?  
Any personal details you provide will be used for the purpose of dealing with your request, enquiry, transaction or application for employment. This may involve disclosing your personal information to companies within the Jaycar Group, or to service providers who assist us in operating our business. These organisations are required to comply with the principles of this Statement.

_Data Security_  
We take steps to protect the personal information we hold against loss, unauthorised access, use, modification or disclosure, and against other misuse. When the personal information that we collect is no longer required, we destroy or delete it in a secure manner, in accordance with our documented procedure.

_Your Choices_  
You can access the personal information that we hold about you, and you can ask us to correct the personal information we hold about you. For more information, see our complete Privacy Policy which located on our website. If you are listed on one or more of our media or network email lists you can opt out at any time. You can unsubscribe by using the ‘unsubscribe’ link in our emails.

_Our Obligations_  
Jaycar is bound by the information Privacy Principles in the Privacy Act.

_How to Contact us_  
For further information contact us on privacyofficer@jaycar.com.au or alternatively you can write to Privacy Officer, Jaycar Electronics PO Box 7172 Silverwater NSW 1811, Australia.
